https://ce.uiu.ac.bd/faculty/asif

Skip to content * DSpace * Library * Faculty Members * Degree Verification * Important Contact * Apply Online

• Profile Login

Search for: * Home * About Research * Message from Head of Department * Major Divisions * Mission, Vision & PEO'S
* Strength of CE, UIU * Program Research * Undergraduate * Course Sequence * Course System * Degree Requirement *
Registration and Payment System * Course Drop and Withdrawal * Scholarship * Tuition Fees * Admission * Research
Research * Field of Interest * Faculty Members * Facilities Research * Lab Facilities * Class Room and Study Room Facilities
* IT Service * Library * Resources Research * Academic Calendar * Curriculum * Forms * Testing & Consultancy Research *
Testing facilities * Application form * Activities * Notices * Contact

Mr. Md. Asif Bin Kabir

Assistant Professor, Department of Civil Engineering

ROOM: 735 (B) PABX: 7202 Email: asif@ce.uiu.ac.bd * Home * Faculty Profiles

- Biography
- Education
- Academic Experience
- Professional Experience
- Research
- Awards and Scholarships
- Publication

Biography

Md Asif Bin Kabir is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Civil Engineering at United International University (UIU), Bangladesh since January 2022. His responsibility includes the Lab-in-Charge for Civil Engineering Department. He completed his M.Sc. at Lakehead University, Canada and his undergraduate studies at Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET), Bangladesh. His research interests lie in the area of Structural Engineering in addition to the application of artificial intelligence (AI) in structural engineering domain. His research experience includes working on industry (CISC, NSERC) funded projects with strong publication record for both journal and conferences. He is a recipient of several awards and scholarships from both home and abroad. Asif has both academic and industrial experiences throughout his professional career. Prior joining to UIU, he was a faculty member for several private universities in Bangladesh during his academic career. He has taught a variety of courses related to â€~Structural Engineering' including the basic â€~Mechanics' courses as well as has mentored undergraduate students both international and domestic level for their final year thesis or projects. He has attended various training sessions regarding Outcome Based Education (OBE) within the varsity he has served. He has a good collaboration for research with local and international universities. Asif's industrial career includes serving as a Structural Design Engineer in a consultancy firm in Bangladesh. He has supervised multiple significant projects and has appreciated as a technically savvy personal. He provides consultancy service for the local industry and has active industry-academia correlation. Last but not the least, he

Education

M.Sc in Civil (Structural) Engineering, April 2021 Lakehead University, Thunder Bay, ON, Canada B.Sc in Civil Engineering, September 2015 Khulna University of Engineering and Technology (KUET), Khulna, Bangladesh

Academic Experience

Assistant Professor(January 2022-present)

Department of Civil Engineering
United International University
Dhaka, Bangladesh Lecturer (May 2021- December 2021)
Department of Civil Engineering
Presidency University

Dhaka, Bangladesh Graduate Research Assistant (September 2019-April 2021)

Department of Civil Engineering (RIBS Lab),

Lakehead University, Thunder bay, ON, Canada Lecturer (June 2016- June 2018)

Department of Civil Engineering

World University of Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh Adjunct Lecturer (September 2018- August 2019)

Department of Civil Engineering

World University of Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Professional Experience

Structural Design Engineer (May 2018-August 2019)

YGEN Engineering Ltd.

Mohakhali(DOHS), Dhaka, Bangladesh Major Projects:

â€" Design of a three story mezzanine steel building (Total Area- 60000 sft)

â€" Design of a 45m high oil refinery plant

â€" Design of industrial shed having different ridge orientation.

â€" Design of industrial shed including crane structure.

Research

Research Interest * Behavior of steel structures under dynamic loading * Numerical analysis of structures * Large scale experiment * Application of artificial intelligence in structural engineering

Research Projects Project Title: Design of Exposed Column Base Plate Connection Subjected to Combined Axial Load and

Biaxial Bending

Role: Project Lead (September 2019-April 2021)

Sponsor: Canadian Institute of Steel Construction (CISC) Project Title: HealthBox â€" A Modular Solution for Expanding

Hospital's Capacities during the COVID-19 Pandemic

Role: Project Lead (June 2020-April 2021)

Sponsor: NSERC-Alliance Grants

Awards and Scholarships

Research Assistantship (2019-2021)

Lakehead University, Canada Academic Excellence Award (2020)

Lakehead University, Canada Faculty of Engineering Award (2019-2021)

Lakehead University, Canada International Graduate Student Award (2019-2021)

Lakehead University, Canada Bangladesh Sweden Trust Fund (2019)

Government of the People's Republic of Bangladesh University Merit Scholarship (2012-2015)

Khulna University of Engineering & Technology (KUET), Khulna, Bangladesh

Publication

Journal Papers

2023## Application of Machine Learning Models and SHAP to Examine Crashes Involving Young Drivers in New Jersey Publication: International Journal of Transportation Science and Technology Author List: Md Asif Bin Kabir, Ahmed Sajid Hasan, Subasish Das, Mohammad Jalayer 2022## Severity modeling of work zone crashes in New Jersey using machine learning models. Publication: Journal of Transportation Safety & Security Author List: Md Asif Bin Kabir, Mohammad Jalayer, Subasish Das, Ahmed Sajid Hasan 2021## Failure mode identification of column base plate connection using data-driven machine learning techniques Publication: Engineering Structures Author List: Md. Asif Bin Kabir, AHM Muntasir Billah, Ahmed Sajid Hasan 2020## Development of Performance Limit States for Concrete Bridge Piers with High Strength Concrete and High Strength Steel Reinforcement. Publication: Canadian Journal of Civil Engineering Author List: Md Asif Bin Kabir, A.H.M Muntasir Billah, Md Asif Bin Kabir, A.H.M Muntasir Billah, Md Asif Bin Kabir, A.H.M Muntasir Billah

Follow Us

About UIU

- Why UIU
- Vision Mission Goals
- General Information
- UIU Campus
- Guiding Principles
- Ranking & Accreditation
- Convocation
- Gallery
- Media
- Career
- Contact

Departments

- Dept. of CSE
- B.Sc in Data Science
- Dept. of EEE
- Dept. of Civil Engineering
- Dept. of Pharmacy
- Dept. of English
- Dept. of EDS
- Dept. of MSJ
- SoBE (BBA, AIS, MBA, EMBA)
- Dept. of Economics
- Dept. of BGE

Admission

- Admission
- Tuition Fees & Waiver
- Admission Requirements
- Admission Test Result
- Admission Procedure
- Admission Dates
- International Students' Admission
- Global Opportunities
- International Collaboration
- FAQ

Important Links

- Time Schedule of Shuttle Services
- Student Transportation Service
- Payment Procedure
- Student e-Resources
- Important Contact

Quick Links

- UCAM
- eLMS
- Parent Portal
- Online Classroom Booking
- Degree Verification
- Necessary Forms
- Notice
- News
- Event
- CE Old Website